Inventory of the Dale O. Hall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Dale O. Hall papers
1908-1946
96048
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (5.2 linear feet)
The collection relates to American military training in the United States during World War II, military mapping in the Pacific Theater, and the postwar occupation of Japan. It consists of correspondence, diary, printed matter, photographs, and miscellany.
Hall, Dale O.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Dale O. Hall was a Technician 5 in the United States Army and member of the 64th Engineer Topographic Battalion from 1944 to 1946.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection relates to American military training in the United States during World War II, military mapping in the Pacific Theater, and the postwar occupation of Japan. The majority of the collection is correspondence between Dale O. Hall and his family and friends during his assignments to different Engineer Topographic Battalions in World War II.
The collection also includes a variety of printed material that illustrates Hall's daily life in the service (magazines, performance brochures, movie tickets, official memos). Much of this printed material was mailed by Dale to his family with his letters, to be saved as souvenirs, and is mainly arranged separately from his letters.
United States. Army. Engineer Base Topographic Battalion, 64th.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Military government.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.; World War, 1939-1945--Cartography.
- Personal materials, 1936-1946 (Folder 1)
  - School work and material, 1936-1946 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Finances and insurance, 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Diary, 1943 (Folder 1: 3)
- Printed materials, 1939-1946 (Folder 1-2)
  - U.S. Forest Service memoranda and material, 1939-1942 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Newsletters and newspaper clippings, 1943-1946 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Newsletters and newspaper clippings, 1945-1946 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Religious material, 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 7-8)
  - Army memoranda and material, 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 9-10)
  - Army entertainment, tickets and programs, 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Army entertainment, tickets and programs, 1945 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-1945 (Folder 2: 2-6)
- Photographs of family, friends, U.S. Army soldiers, and Tokyo, 1908-1939 (Box-folder 2: 7, 13)
- Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Folder 3-12)
  - 1943 (Folder 3-6)
    - February (Folder 3: 1-2)
    - March (Folder 3: 3-5)
    - April (Folder 3: 6-8)
    - May (Folder 4: 1-2)
    - June (Folder 4: 3-4)
    - July (Folder 4: 5-6)
    - August (Folder 4: 7)
    - September (Folder 5: 1-2)
    - October (Folder 5: 3-4)
    - November (Folder 5: 5-6)
    - December (Folder 6: 1-4)
  - 1944 (Folder 7-9)
    - January (Folder 7: 1-2)
    - February (Folder 7: 3)
    - March (Folder 7: 4)
    - April (Folder 7: 5-7)
    - May (Folder 7: 8)
    - June (Folder 8: 1-2)
    - July (Folder 8: 3-5)
    - August (Folder 8: 6-7)
    - September (Folder 9: 1-2)
    - October (Folder 9: 3-4)
    - November (Folder 9: 5-7)
    - December (Folder 9: 8-10)
  - 1945 (Folder 10-12)
    - January (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - February (Folder 10: 3-4)
    - March (Folder 10: 5-6)
    - April (Folder 11: 1-2)
    - May (Folder 11: 3-5)
    - June (Folder 11: 6-8)
    - July (Folder 11: 9-10)
    - August (Folder 11: 11)
    - August (contd.) (Folder 12: 1)
    - September (Folder 12: 2-3)
    - October (Folder 12: 4-5)
    - October (Folder 12: 4-5)
    - November (Folder 12: 6)
    - December (Folder 12: 7-8)
  - 1946 (Folder 12)
    - January (Folder 12: 9)
    - February (Folder 12: 10)